<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="./FGDC_Plus.xsl"?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <title>Seagrasses</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>The seagrass data was created for the AWE Project being run by the Nature Conservancy. The dataset is complilation of effort by different contributors and combines different datasets. The spatial information comes from six (6) different datasets. 1.) The Ph.D. work of Kim Baldwin at the University of the West Indies Cave Hill and the generation of the Marine Space-use Information System (MarSIS) resulted in a benthic habitat file which she created by heads up digitizing effort using 1 meter IKONOS imagery. About 60% of the features by number are from this effort. 2.) Contract work by Matthew Jones as part of The Nature Conservancy contract for Summer 2011 using LANDSAT 1999 images contrubited to about 10% of the features by number. 3.) A project dataset shared by the Planning Department of St. Vincent and the Grenadines which was developed for the SVG CRIS. Data was digitized from LANDSAT 1999 images by Alan Mills and others. About 8% of features by number are from this effort. 4). A contractor of the Nature Conservancy working from BYU digitized seagrass from 2007 aerial imagery for St. Vincent and the Grenadines. About 15% of the features by number are from this effort. 5.) Again, a contractor of the Nature Conservancy working from BYU digitized seagrass features from WorldView2 2010 orthophotos for Grenada. About 7% of the features by number are from this effort. 6.) A contractor of the Nature Conservancy, Jerry Mitchell, mapped seagrasses for the area surrounding Woburn Clarke's Court Bay, Grenada.</abstract>
      <purpose>These data were created under the direction of The Nature Conservancy for the Ecosystem Based Adaptation in the Grenadine Bank project (AWE). This project is built on the hypothesis that the neighboring and ecologically connected small island states in the Grenadine Bank can enhance the resilience of people and nature to climate change impacts by protecting, restoring and sustainably managing marine and coastal systems and strengthening community capacity for adaptation.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-61.795539</westbc>
        <eastbc>-61.142849</eastbc>
        <northbc>13.161136</northbc>
        <southbc>11.989032</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>GIS Data User AgreementAny Geographic Information System (GIS) data or information received from The Nature Conservancy (TNC) or downloaded from a TNC site (collectively “GIS Data”) is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 License (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/3.0/). More specific limitations of this data are stated below. By using this information, you acknowledge that you have read, understood, and accepted the terms and conditions stated in this GIS Data User Agreement. TNC reserves the right to change this Agreement at any time and without notice. Your use of this information shall constitute your agreement to be bound by this Agreement and any changes.The user hereby acknowledges that the GIS Data is subject to constant change and that its accuracy, including but not limited to, its accuracy as to labeling, dimensions, boundaries, placement or location of any map features therein, cannot be guaranteed. All GIS Data is provided as is, with potential faults, errors and without warranty of any kind, expressed or implied, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. Additionally, TNC does not warrant that the information contained in this GIS Data will meet the user's requirements or that the operation of the GIS Data will be uninterrupted or error free, or that data defects will be corrected. The entire risk as to the quality, performance and usefulness of the GIS Data rests with the user.The user, in using this GIS Data, hereby releases TNC, their agents, consultants, contractors or employees from any and all claims, actions, or causes of action for damages including, but not limited to, any costs of recovering, reprogramming or reproducing any programs or data stored in or used with the GIS Data, damage to property, damages for personal injury or for any lost profits, lost savings, or other special, incidental or consequential damages arising out of the use of or inability to use the GIS Data, even if such parties have been advised of the possibility of such damage. User agrees to indemnify and hold harmless TNC, their agents, consultants, contractors and employees from any and all liability claims or damages to any person or property arising from or connected with the use of the GIS Data.Further Data RestrictionsUse of the GIS Data is limited to academic or scientific purposes and may not be used for profitable purposes or by a for-profit corporation. The user hereby commits to acknowledge The Nature Conservancy as the data source and compiler when GIS Data received from TNC (through formal delivery or from a website) is used in the preparation of reports, papers, publications, maps and any other products. Any use, display or incorporation of GIS Data shall include the date on which such information was provided.The user also agrees to provide TNC, at no cost to TNC, a digital copy of any Geo-Spatial Data, tabular data, reports, imagery, drawing(s), plan(s), and any other form of result that were derived directly or indirectly from the use of these data provided by TNC along with its associated metadata.To ensure that appropriate documentation and data limitations are provided, downloaded data should not be redistributed to third-party users or uploaded to a central server unless written permission is granted by the TNC’s Caribbean Program GIS data manager (caribgis@tnc.org) and Caribbean Program Director (Luis Solorzano: luis.solorzano@TNC.ORG).When such GIS Data is used the following disclaimer and waiver of liability shall be included and displayed prominently so as to alert any person viewing or utilizing this information:NOTICE: It is understood that, while The Nature Conservancy and its partners of information have no indication or reason to believe that there are inaccuracies or defects in information incorporated in the base map, The Nature Conservancy and its data partners make NO REPRESENTATIONS OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE, NOR ARE ANY SUCH WARRANTIES TO BE IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO THE INFORMATION OR DATA, FURNISHED HEREIN.</useconst>
    <datacred>The Nature Conservancy (2012). Contact Conservation Information Manager, caribgis@tnc.org.</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.3.3600</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>1614</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <mapproj>
          <mapprojn>WGS 1984 UTM Zone 20N</mapprojn>
          <transmer>
            <sfctrmer>0.9996</sfctrmer>
            <longcm>-63.0</longcm>
            <latprjo>0.0</latprjo>
            <feast>500000.0</feast>
            <fnorth>0.0</fnorth>
          </transmer>
        </mapproj>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.000000002220024164500956</absres>
            <ordres>0.000000002220024164500956</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>meter</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Seagrasses</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Classes of seagrass habitat such as sparse, dense or simply seagrass.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TYPES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Source of where feature was digitized or pulled from</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SOURCE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DIGITISER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Name of person who digitized feature for the SVG CRIS product</attrdef>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DATE_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Date of when feature was digitized during the SVG CRIS product</attrdef>
        <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PROBLEMS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Problems that were encountered when digitizing. This field began with the SVG CRIS product.</attrdef>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Shapefile</formname>
          <transize>0.367</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt />
      </digform>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20120327</metd>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>